>> Jem Young: 互联网工作方式如何 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: How does the Internet work?
有人捅了它不是萨姆
Someone take a stab at it, not Sam.
还有谁
Anybody else?
抛出答案。
Throw out an answer.
这是我最喜欢的面试问题之一。
This is one of my favorite
interview questions.
我不经常问，但它是其中之一，你能理解什么 ?
I don't ask it that often, but
it's one of those, what do you understand?
你的知识在哪里，在前端是后端，
Where's your knowledge lies,
at the front end, is it the back end,
是联网的地方吗
is it networking, is it somewhere?
如果你是工程师你的理解就在某个地方
If you're an engineer,
your understanding lies somewhere.
除非你是我不知道是个自驾的汽车工程师
Unless you're like, I don't know,
a self-driving car engineer or
一个桥梁建筑工程师，好的，有很多不同类型的工程师。
a bridge building engineer, okay, there's
lots of different types of engineer.
但如果你是一个在网络上工作的软件工程师
But if you're a software
engineer that works on the web,
最重要的是软件工程师，你至少应该知道其中的一部分。
which is most software engineers, you
should know at least some part of this.
那么，互联网是如何运作的呢 ?
So how does the Internet work?
有人吗 什么都扔了
Anybody?
Just throw out anything.
没有错误的答案。
There are no wrong answers.
我们今天都在学习
We're all learning here today.
>> 扬声器 2: 一群计算机相互交谈。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: A bunch of
computers talking to each other.
> > Jem Young: 对我来说足够了。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Good enough for me.
是啊是一堆电脑在交谈
Yeah, it's a bunch of computers
talking to each other.
那么，互联网是如何运作的呢 ?
So how does the Internet work, though?
这就是互联网的内容。
That's kinda what the Internet is.
>> 扬声器 2: 请求和响应的批次，对吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Lots of requests and
responses, right?
> > Jem Young: 是的，是的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, yeah.
>> Jem Young: 是的，很多要求和回应，对我也有好处。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, lots of requests and
responses, that's good for me, too.
>> 扬声器 3: 我只知道有文件和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I just
know there's files and
信息包被传递到不同的领域我不知道
packets of files get passed
across different, I don't know.
>> Jem Young: 是的，有时是文件，包和计算机。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, sometimes it's files,
packets, computers.
我认为我们认为互联网的很多东西是我们想到的网页浏览器，
I think a lot of what we think of the
Internet is we think of web browsers, and
我们想，我不知道，可能是流式电影之类的。
we think of, I don't know, maybe
streaming movies or something like that.
人们与互联网互动的主要原因是万维网，
Mostly what people interact with
the Internet is the World Wide Web,
那就是 www 点的点
that's the www dot something.
我们都知道但是
We all know that, but
我保证我的未来儿子不知道 www 代表什么
I guarantee my future son will
not know what www stands for.
只是当你输入的时候，但那是万维网，
It's just that when you type in,
but that's the World Wide Web,
那只是互联网的一部分
that's just a part of the Internet.
还有 FTP 网络上运行的东西
There's still FTP,
there's things that run over the Internet,
所以有些东西像 BitTorrent 或者电影串流
so there's things like a BitTorrent or
movie streaming.
有很多其他的例子，但是大多数人，对，马克。
There's lots of other examples,
but most people, yes, Mark.
>演讲者 4: Andrew Online 说这是一系列的管道。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: Andrew Online
says it's a series of tubes.
>> 演讲者 3: [LAUGH] >> Jem Young:
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: That was the answer I was
其实是在找
actually looking for.
他们会在第二次被雇用
They would be hired in a second.
它是一系列的管子。
It is a series of tubes.
但就像每个网站都是一系列的请求
But like every site,
it's a series of requests and
不同设备的响应只是相互对话。
responses by different devices
just talking to each other.
所以我想用最简单的定义
So I use the simplest definition
I could think of, and
我没查过这个尽管我可以
I didn't look this up,
even though I could have.
我只是说这是一系列全球互联互通的设备。
I just said it's a series of
globally interconnected devices.
我会说这是一系列公开互联的设备。
And I'll say it's a series of
publicly interconnected devices.
那是网络我们都知道
That's the Internet,
that's the thing we all know,
这就是我们现在所使用的
it's the thing we're using right now.
这就是你在家中的经历和流
Thing that is running through and
streaming to you at home,
你在教室里
you in the classroom.
这跟内部网有点不同
That's a little different
from the intranet.
内部网就像互联网，但它是私人的。
The intranet is like the Internet,
but it's private.
有多少人使用 VPN，虚拟专用网，用于工作?
How many people use a VPN,
a Virtual Private Network, for work?
是的大部分公司都这么做
Yeah, most companies do.
这是最佳做法之一。
It's one of the best practices.
所以如果你在 VPN 上，你就在网上。
So if you're on a VPN,
you're on an intranet.
这只是不同服务器之间相互对话的私人互联网
Which is just a private Internet of
different servers talking to each other,
但外面是不可能的
but it's inaccessible from the outside.
为什么这很重要
Why is that important?
在某个时候你可能会听到 " 冥顽不化 " 一词
At some point,
you may hear the term intranets,
你可能会听到广域网广域网的情况很相似
you may hear the term WAN wide
area network, pretty similar.
局域网才是这个教室的网络。
Local area network would be
Internet just for this classroom.
所以如果我有服务器运行，实际上有服务器在那边运行，
So if I had a server running, actually
there are server's running over there,
有一个服务器在那边运行，而且它是唯一可以访问的。
there's a server running over there,
and it was only accessible.
这将是一个局域网，不能从外部进入。
That would be a local area network,
that is not accessible from the outside.